Guide to the Indonesian National Legislative Election Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Indonesian national legislative election collection
1999-1999
MS 1998
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.02
(2 boxes)
The collection consists of posters, leaflets, banners, flags and other materials distributed by some of the 48 various Indonesian political parties and movements preceding and leading up to the national legislative elections held on June 7, 1999. This was the first free election held in Indonesia since 1955.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of flyers, leaflets, flags, banners, posters, and other materials distributed by various Indonesian political parties in the national legislative campaign beginning on May 19, 1999 and lasting until June 4, 1999. The campaign was divided into three time periods with different groups of parties allowed only during their allocated campaign period. Of the over 100 parties that were formed only 48 were allowed to register as official parties for the election. These parties contested the 462 seats available in the People's Representative Council, with a further 38 seats reserved for the military. The process of counting ballots and allocating seats in the Representative Council was time consuming, but the final results of the election awarded seats to 21 parties, with the Indonesian Democratic Party and Golkar Party receiving the largest number of seats.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged according to format.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Southeast Asian Collection Curator, 2014.
Elections -- Indonesia; Political parties -- Indonesia; Indonesia
- Inventory
  - Photographs and member list of Kabinet Persatuan Nasional (National Unity Cabinet), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Pictures and list of cabinet members who served under President Abdurrahaman Wahid and Vice President Megawati Sukarnoputi from October 1999 until July 2001, and intended to protect the rights of the parties in the Representative Council.
  - Flyers and leaflets from various political parties, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Partai Rakyat Demokratik (16-PRD) flag with a red star, 1999 (Box 2)
    The red star is the emblem of this industrial party and the number 16 represents the party's number on the ballot.
  - Partai Gokar yellow flag, 1999 (Box 2)
    With tree emblem and party motto "Golongan Karya" and the number 33 representing this party's position on the ballot.
  - Partai Gokar yellow polo shirt, 1999 (Box 2)
    With emblem on chest and sleeve.
  - Partai Syarikat Islam Indonesia (10 PSII ) flag, 1999 (Box 2)
    Black background with Arabic script and star at top. The number 10 again represents the position of this party on the ballot.
  - Partai Republik (28) flag, 1999 (Box 2)
    Orange flag with the party emblem.
  - Partai Republik (28) t-shirt, 1999 (Box 2)
    Orange, with the party emblem on the chest and the name of the party on the back.
  - Partai Aliansi Demokrat Indonesia (4 PADI) flags, 1999 (Box 2)
    2 copies of this with flag with images of a rice padi on an orange background.
  - Partai Solidaritas Pekerja (23 PSP) flag, 1999 (Box 2)
    White flag with a blue dove as the party emblem.
  - Partai Buruh Nasional (37 PBN) flag, 1999 (Box 2)